 export const history =  [
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20of%20these%20countries%20was%20sea%20charted%20in%201500%20by%20the%20Portuguese%20maritime%20explorations%3F",
"correct_answer": "Brazil",
"incorrect_answers": [
"India",
"Mozambique",
"Madagascar"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "During%20the%20Mongolian%20invasions%20of%20Japan%2C%20what%20were%20the%20Mongol%20boats%20mostly%20stopped%20by%3F",
"correct_answer": "Typhoons",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Tornados",
"Economic%20depression",
"Samurai"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20what%20year%20did%20Neil%20Armstrong%20and%20Buzz%20Aldrin%20land%20on%20the%20moon%3F",
"correct_answer": "1969",
"incorrect_answers": [
"1965",
"1966",
"1973"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "%20What%20Russian%20automatic%20gas-operated%20assault%20rifle%20was%20developed%20in%20the%20Soviet%20Union%20in%201947%2C%20and%20is%20still%20popularly%20used%20today%3F",
"correct_answer": "AK-47",
"incorrect_answers": [
"RPK",
"M16",
"MG%2042"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Joseph%20Smith%20was%20the%20founder%20of%20what%20religion%3F",
"correct_answer": "Mormonism",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Buddhism",
"Christianity",
"Hinduism"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20historical%20event%20was%20Tchaikovsky%27s%201812%20Overture%20referencing%3F",
"correct_answer": "The%20Napoleonic%20Wars",
"incorrect_answers": [
"The%20American%20War%20of%201812",
"The%20Russian%20Revolution",
"The%20Charge%20of%20the%20Light%20Brigade%20%28Crimean%20War%29"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "America%27s%20Strategic%20Defense%20System%20during%20the%20Cold%20War%20was%20nicknamed%20after%20this%20famous%20movie.",
"correct_answer": "Star%20Wars",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Jaws",
"Blade%20Runner",
"Alien"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Who%20was%20the%20first%20explorer%20to%20sail%20to%20North%20America%3F",
"correct_answer": "Leif%20Erikson",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Christopher%20Columbus",
"Amerigo%20Vespucci",
"Ferdinand%20Magellan"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20what%20year%20was%20the%20famous%2045%20foot%20tall%20Hollywood%20sign%20first%20erected%3F",
"correct_answer": "1923",
"incorrect_answers": [
"1903",
"1913",
"1933"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "The%20Battle%20of%20the%20Somme%20in%20World%20War%20I%20took%20place%20in%20which%20country%3F",
"correct_answer": "France",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Germany",
"Italy",
"Austria"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "When%20did%20Jamaica%20recieve%20its%20independence%20from%20England%3F%20",
"correct_answer": "1962",
"incorrect_answers": [
"1492",
"1963",
"1987"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20of%20the%20following%20ancient%20Near%20Eastern%20peoples%20still%20exists%20as%20a%20modern%20ethnic%20group%3F",
"correct_answer": "Assyrians",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Babylonians",
"Hittites",
"Elamites"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20of%20the%20following%20is%20NOT%20classified%20as%20a%20Semetic%20language%3F",
"correct_answer": "Sumerian",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Maltese",
"Akkadian",
"Mandaic"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "All%20of%20the%20following%20are%20names%20of%20the%20Seven%20Warring%20States%20EXCEPT%3A",
"correct_answer": "Zhai%20%28%E7%BF%9F%29",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Zhao%20%28%E8%B6%99%29",
"Qin%20%28%E7%A7%A6%29",
"Qi%20%28%E9%BD%8A%29"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "One%20of%20the%20deadliest%20pandemics%2C%20the%20%22Spanish%20Flu%22%2C%20killed%20off%20what%20percentage%20of%20the%20human%20world%20population%20at%20the%20time%3F",
"correct_answer": "3%20to%206%20percent",
"incorrect_answers": [
"6%20to%2010%20percent",
"1%20to%203%20percent",
"less%20than%201%20percent"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "According%20to%20scholarly%20estimates%2C%20what%20percentage%20of%20the%20world%20population%20at%20the%20time%20died%20due%20to%20Tamerlane%27s%20conquests%3F",
"correct_answer": "5%25",
"incorrect_answers": [
"1%25",
"3%25",
"%3C1%25"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20infamous%20European%20traitor%20was%20known%20as%20%22the%20last%20person%20to%20enter%20Parliament%20with%20honest%20intentions%22%3F",
"correct_answer": "Guy%20Fawkes",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Robert%20Catesby",
"Francis%20Tresham",
"Everard%20Digby"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "On%20which%20day%20did%20construction%20start%20on%20%22The%20Pentagon%22%2C%20the%20headquarters%20for%20the%20United%20States%20Department%20of%20Defense%3F",
"correct_answer": "September%2011%2C%201941",
"incorrect_answers": [
"June%2015%2C%201947",
"January%2015%2C%201943",
"September%202%2C%201962"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "How%20old%20was%20Lyndon%20B.%20Johnson%20when%20he%20assumed%20the%20role%20of%20President%20of%20the%20United%20States%3F",
"correct_answer": "55",
"incorrect_answers": [
"50",
"60",
"54"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20Apollo%20mission%20was%20the%20last%20one%20in%20NASA%27s%20Apollo%20program%3F",
"correct_answer": "Apollo%2017",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Apollo%2013",
"Apollo%2011",
"Apollo%2015"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20the%20War%20of%20the%20Pacific%20%281879%20-%201883%29%2C%20Bolivia%20lost%20its%20access%20to%20the%20Pacific%20Ocean%20after%20being%20defeated%20by%20which%20South%20American%20country%3F",
"correct_answer": "Chile",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Peru",
"Brazil",
"Argentina"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "How%20many%20times%20was%20Albert%20Einstein%20married%20in%20his%20lifetime%3F",
"correct_answer": "Twice",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Five",
"Thrice",
"Once"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20nationality%20was%20sultan%20Saladin%3F",
"correct_answer": "Kurdish",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Arab",
"Egyptian",
"Syrian"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20building%20was%20set%20aflame%20on%20August%2024th%2C%201812%3F",
"correct_answer": "The%20White%20House",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Parliament%20Building",
"Grand%20National%20Assembly%20Building",
"Palace%20of%20the%20Nation"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20is%20the%20mnemonic%20device%20for%20remembering%20the%20fates%20of%20the%20wives%20of%20Henry%20VIII%3F",
"correct_answer": "Divorced%2C%20Beheaded%2C%20Died%2C%20Divorced%2C%20Beheaded%2C%20Survived",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Beheaded%2C%20Died%2C%20Divorced%2C%20Divorced%2C%20Beheaded%2C%20Survived",
"Died%2C%20Beheaded%2C%20Divorced%2C%20Beheaded%2C%20Survived%2C%20Divorced",
"Survived%2C%20Beheaded%2C%20Died%2C%20Divorced%2C%20Divorced%2C%20Beheaded"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20American%20civilization%20is%20the%20source%20of%20the%20belief%20that%20the%20world%20would%20end%20or%20drastically%20change%20on%20December%2021st%2C%202012%3F",
"correct_answer": "The%20Mayans",
"incorrect_answers": [
"The%20Incas",
"The%20Aztecs",
"The%20Navajos"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "When%20did%20Norway%20get%20its%20constitution%3F",
"correct_answer": "1814",
"incorrect_answers": [
"1932",
"1905",
"1854"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "When%20did%20Norway%20become%20free%20from%20Sweden%3F",
"correct_answer": "1905",
"incorrect_answers": [
"1925",
"1814",
"1834"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20historical%20conflict%20killed%20the%20most%20people%3F",
"correct_answer": "World%20War%20II",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Taiping%20Rebellion",
"Three%20Kingdoms%20War",
"Mongol%20conquests"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Who%20was%20the%20first%20president%20born%20in%20the%20independent%20United%20States%3F",
"correct_answer": "Martin%20Van%20Buren",
"incorrect_answers": [
"John%20Adams",
"George%20Washington",
"James%20Monroe%20"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20was%20the%20unofficial%20name%20for%20Germany%20between%201919%20and%201933%3F",
"correct_answer": "Weimar%20Republic",
"incorrect_answers": [
"German%20Democratic%20Republic",
"Federal%20Republic%20of%20Germany",
"Oesterreich%20"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "The%20United%20States%20Army%20Air%20Corps%20became%20the%20United%20States%20Air%20Force%20on%20what%20date%3F",
"correct_answer": "September%2018%2C%201947",
"incorrect_answers": [
"December%2014%2C%201946",
"October%2027%2C%201945",
"November%2008%2C%201944"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20World%20War%20I%2C%20what%20was%20the%20name%20of%20the%20alliance%20of%20Germany%2C%20Austria-Hungary%2C%20the%20Ottoman%20Empire%2C%20and%20Bulgaria%3F",
"correct_answer": "The%20Central%20Powers",
"incorrect_answers": [
"The%20Axis%20Powers",
"The%20Federation%20of%20Empires",
"Authoritarian%20Alliance"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20what%20year%20did%20the%20Berlin%20Wall%20fall%3F",
"correct_answer": "1989",
"incorrect_answers": [
"1987",
"1991",
"1993"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20country%20was%20an%20allied%20power%20in%20World%20War%20II%3F",
"correct_answer": "Soviet%20Union",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Italy",
"Germany",
"Japan"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "When%20was%20the%20People%27s%20Republic%20of%20China%20founded%3F",
"correct_answer": "October%201%2C%201949",
"incorrect_answers": [
"April%203%2C%201947",
"May%207%2C%201945",
"December%206%2C%201950"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "On%20which%20aircraft%20carrier%20did%20the%20Doolitte%20Raid%20launch%20from%20on%20April%2018%2C%201942%20during%20World%20War%20II%3F",
"correct_answer": "USS%20Hornet",
"incorrect_answers": [
"USS%20Enterprise",
"USS%20Lexington",
"USS%20Saratoga"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20was%20the%20code%20name%20for%20the%20German%20invasion%20of%20the%20Soviet%20Union%20in%20WW2%3F",
"correct_answer": "Operation%20Barbarossa",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Operation%20Kaiserschlact",
"Operation%20Unthinkable",
"Operation%20Molotov"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "When%20did%20construction%20of%20the%20Suez%20Canal%20finish%3F",
"correct_answer": "1869",
"incorrect_answers": [
"1859",
"1860",
"1850"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20year%20did%20the%20Vietnam%20War%20end%3F",
"correct_answer": "1975",
"incorrect_answers": [
"1978",
"1967",
"1969"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20of%20the%20following%20Presidents%20of%20the%20United%20States%20was%20assassinated%3F",
"correct_answer": "William%20McKinley",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Lyndon%20Johnson",
"Chester%20Arthur",
"Franklin%20Roosevelt"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Who%20crowned%20Charlemagne%20as%20Holy%20Roman%20Emperor%20on%20Christmas%20Day%20in%20800%3F",
"correct_answer": "Pope%20Leo%20III",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Pope%20Urban%20IV",
"Pope%20Stephen%20V",
"Pope%20Valentine"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20of%20these%201900s%20tanks%20were%20designed%20and%20built%20BEFORE%20the%20others%3F",
"correct_answer": "Renault%20FT",
"incorrect_answers": [
"M4%20Sherman",
"%20Panzer%20IV",
"Cromwell%20"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Who%20was%20the%20first%20Chancellor%20of%20a%20united%20Germany%20in%201871%3F%20",
"correct_answer": "Otto%20Von%20Bismark",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Kaiser%20Wilhelm%20",
"Fredrick%20the%202nd",
"Robert%20Koch"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "When%20did%20the%20Crisis%20of%20the%20Third%20Century%20begin%3F",
"correct_answer": "235%20AD",
"incorrect_answers": [
"235%20BC",
"242%20AD",
"210%20AD"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "The%20Panama%20Canal%20was%20finished%20under%20the%20administration%20of%20which%20U.S.%20president%3F",
"correct_answer": "Woodrow%20Wilson",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Franklin%20Delano%20Roosevelt",
"Herbert%20Hoover",
"Theodore%20Roosevelt"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20of%20these%20founding%20fathers%20of%20the%20United%20States%20of%20America%20later%20became%20president%3F",
"correct_answer": "James%20Monroe",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Alexander%20Hamilton",
"Samuel%20Adams",
"Roger%20Sherman"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20of%20these%20facilities%20was%20not%20present%20on%20the%20Titanic%3F",
"correct_answer": "Fainting%20room",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Turkish%20bath",
"Kennel",
"Squash%20court"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "The%20fraudelent%20doctor%20John%20R.%20Brinkley%20acummulated%20great%20fame%20and%20wealth%20in%20the%20early%201900s%20offering%20what%20service%3F",
"correct_answer": "Goat%20testicles%20transplant",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Pig%20blood%20transfusion",
"Cow%20liver%20transplant",
"Turkey%20breast%20implants"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "John%20Moses%20Browning%2C%20the%20designer%20of%20the%20M1918%20BAR%20%28Browning%20Automatic%20Rifle%29%20was%20a%20part%20of%20which%20religion%3F",
"correct_answer": "Mormon",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Catholic",
"Jewish",
"Atheist"
]
}
]